<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Today I Learned</title>
    <link>https://haleyjung.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Today I Learned</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 21:45:06 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://haleyjung.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Naming Convention</title>
      <link>https://haleyjung.github.io/posts/2021/12/naming-convention/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 21:45:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haleyjung.github.io/posts/2021/12/naming-convention/</guid>
      <description>Types of identifier naming convention in computer programming  hungarian case camel case pascal case snake_case  Hungarian notation Hungarian notation, nowadays known as Apps Hungarian, was invented by Charles Simonyi, a Hungarian-American software architect. It was widely implemented at Microsoft when Simonyi was leading the applications group to build the first versions of Microsoft Office.
This naming convention adds a prefix to the identifier name, which indicates the type of the identifier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recommendation Engine: Netflix&#39;s Recommendation Algorithms</title>
      <link>https://haleyjung.github.io/posts/2021/11/recommendation-engine-netflixs-recommendation-algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 14:06:25 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haleyjung.github.io/posts/2021/11/recommendation-engine-netflixs-recommendation-algorithms/</guid>
      <description>Netflix&amp;rsquo;s Recommendation Algorithms Overview  Recommendation algorithms are at the core of the Netflix product. They provide our members with personalized suggestions to reduce the amount of time and frustration to find something great content to watch. Because of the importance of our recommendations, we continually seek to improve them by advancing the state-of-the-art in the field. We do this by using the data about what content our members watch and enjoy along with how they interact with our service to get better at figuring out what the next great movie or TV show for them will be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recommendation Engine: Measurements and Challenges</title>
      <link>https://haleyjung.github.io/posts/2021/11/recommendation-engine-measurements-and-challenges/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 13:38:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haleyjung.github.io/posts/2021/11/recommendation-engine-measurements-and-challenges/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll dive further into the measurements and challenges of a recommendation engine. This post uses references from:
F.O. Isinkaye et al., &amp;ldquo;Recommendation systems: Principles, methods and evaluation,&amp;rdquo; Egyptian Informatics Journal, Cairo University, 13 March 2015.
&amp;ldquo;The Netflix Recommender System: Algorithms, Business Value, and Innovation&amp;rdquo;, ACM Transactions on Management Information Systems, Vol. 6, No. 4, Article 13, December 2015.
To note, I&amp;rsquo;ll be continuously adding more of the latest articles as references.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recommendation Engine: The Introduction</title>
      <link>https://haleyjung.github.io/posts/2021/11/recommendation-engine-the-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2021 16:56:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haleyjung.github.io/posts/2021/11/recommendation-engine-the-introduction/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m at the airport right now, summarizing what I read on the plane about recommendation engine algorithm, as I wait for my next flight. Last night, I opened the Netflix app to download shows I will watch on the plane. I then saw a new feature in the &amp;lsquo;Downloads&amp;rsquo; section that will download a personalized selection of movies and shows for me so that there is always a show for me to watch with or without internet connection!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Missing Contributions on Github</title>
      <link>https://haleyjung.github.io/posts/2021/11/missing-contributions-on-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:03:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haleyjung.github.io/posts/2021/11/missing-contributions-on-github/</guid>
      <description>Why are my contributions missing? After multiple commits on my GitHub for this static site, I noticed that the contributions were not lightening green on my profile. The GitHub page was successfully updated with the latest commit, so at first I thought it was a time lag. GitHub Docs also indicates that &amp;ldquo;you may need to wait for up to 24 hours to see the contribution appear on your contribution graph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Submodules</title>
      <link>https://haleyjung.github.io/posts/2021/11/submodules/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 16:40:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haleyjung.github.io/posts/2021/11/submodules/</guid>
      <description>What is a submodule? A git submodule is a record within a host git repository that points to a specific commit in another external repository. Submodules are very static and only track specific commits. Submodules do not track git refs or branches and are not automatically updated when the host repository is updated.
  It keeps a git repository as a subdirectory of another git repository.
  It serves as a reference to another repo at a particular snapshot of time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Absolute vs Relative Path</title>
      <link>https://haleyjung.github.io/posts/2021/11/absolute-vs-relative-path/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 11:00:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haleyjung.github.io/posts/2021/11/absolute-vs-relative-path/</guid>
      <description>What is a path? A path is a string of characters that identify a specific location of a file or folder on computer. In another word, it represents the directory and file relationship in the operating system. The characters seperated with a slash in URLs represent a path. From this we can also grasp that a path is essential for constructing Uniform Resource Locators (URLs). A path is either absolute or relative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>https://haleyjung.github.io/posts/2021/11/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 10:01:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haleyjung.github.io/posts/2021/11/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>I can no longer remember how many times I&amp;rsquo;ve created this very same file due to various errors and deployment failures.
But, I love debugging! Coming from a field where subjectivity defines the output, I&amp;rsquo;m in love with coding that always has some form of solution.
With that, this shall be my first &amp;lsquo;final&amp;rsquo; post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://haleyjung.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haleyjung.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi!
Today I Learned is a collection of my spark and struggle.
⭐ ⭐ ⭐
When I came across a blog that publish articles on daily learnings
while scrolling through a slack community of software engineers,
I immediately knew this is going to be my next mini project!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
