<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Today I Learned</title>
    <link>https://haleyjung.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Today I Learned</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 23:31:33 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://haleyjung.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Clone</title>
      <link>https://haleyjung.github.io/posts/2022/01/twitter-clone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 23:31:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haleyjung.github.io/posts/2022/01/twitter-clone/</guid>
      <description>Cloning Twitter using jQuery &amp;amp; NodeJS Goal The goal of the Twitter clone project was to create a single page that generates live user feeds.
I used jQuery to create HTML elements and functions to make them dynamic.
Wireframe I began with drawing various wireframes to organize the structure of the overall layout and individual components. The first wireframe was a rough design to indicate the overall layout that was going to be created using CSS Grid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS Grid Layout</title>
      <link>https://haleyjung.github.io/posts/2022/01/css-grid-layout/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 22:52:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haleyjung.github.io/posts/2022/01/css-grid-layout/</guid>
      <description>CSS Grid Layout is great for creating a responsive web page layout.
We can also define an area by giving it a name and then specify the location of that area in the value of the grid-template-areas property, such as:
 header footer sidebar content  The grid-area property can be assigned to a class:
.header { grid-area: hd; } .footer { grid-area: ft; } .content { grid-area: main; } .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prototype &amp; Class Patterns</title>
      <link>https://haleyjung.github.io/posts/2022/01/prototype-class-patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 07:29:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haleyjung.github.io/posts/2022/01/prototype-class-patterns/</guid>
      <description>Prototype Chains  A mechanism for making objects that resemble other objects. Makes one object behave as if it has the same properties of another object by delegating its failed property lookups to that other object at lookup time. Prototype chains make it possible for many child objects to all reflect the properties of one parent object. We can use a prototype object to store all the shared methods and make all our instance objects delegrate to that prototype object, rather than copying all the methods references over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional Classes</title>
      <link>https://haleyjung.github.io/posts/2022/01/functional-classes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 11:20:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haleyjung.github.io/posts/2022/01/functional-classes/</guid>
      <description>Decorator Pattern var Car = function (loc) { var obj = { loc: loc }; ob.mov = function() { // Decorator pattern: creates a new function for every function call  obj.loc++; }; }; var amy = Car(1); amy.move(); var ben = Car(9); ben.move(); Functional Class Pattern with Shared Methods &amp;hellip;or Functional-Shared Pattern
var Car = function (loc) { var obj = { loc: loc }; ob.mov = move; return obj; }; var move = function() { this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript: this</title>
      <link>https://haleyjung.github.io/posts/2022/01/javascript-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 12:07:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haleyjung.github.io/posts/2022/01/javascript-this/</guid>
      <description>What is this?  An identifier for values Designed to support object oriented programming  Binding When a method or constructor function is invoked, this binds to a likely-focal object, so that we can easily access that object.
this is not bound to&amp;hellip; var fn = function (a, b) { log(this); // what is this NOT bound to? };   The function object: {f}
  An instance of the function it appears within: {}</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IIFE &amp; Scopes</title>
      <link>https://haleyjung.github.io/posts/2022/01/iife-scopes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 11:10:24 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haleyjung.github.io/posts/2022/01/iife-scopes/</guid>
      <description>Function Expression vs. Function Declaration The function name can be omitted in function expressions to create anonymous functions while function declarations (statements) require names.
A function expression can be used as an IIFE (Immediately Invoked Function Expression).
//Function Expression let variableName = function() { statements; }; // -&amp;gt; ends with a semicolon because it&amp;#39;s an assignment statement; not part of the function syntax  //Function Declaration function name([param[, param,[..., param]]]) { statements; } Definition of IIFE IIFE, also known as Self-Executing Anonymous Function, is a JavaScript function that runs as soon as it is defined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Function Call vs Function Invocation</title>
      <link>https://haleyjung.github.io/posts/2022/01/function-call-vs-function-invocation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 10:44:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haleyjung.github.io/posts/2022/01/function-call-vs-function-invocation/</guid>
      <description>Function Call  Directly telling the function to run. The combined process of fully applying the function then invoking it, usually with the added semantic that the code will wait for a return value.  Function Invocation  i.e. Function got executed. Indirectly refers to the calling statement. The process required to schedule the function with its fully bound arguments for execution. Includes pushing arguments onto the stack and transferring the PC to the new address, placing messages/objects/functions/thunks on a queue for later execution or various other RPC systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DOM</title>
      <link>https://haleyjung.github.io/posts/2022/01/dom/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 10:50:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haleyjung.github.io/posts/2022/01/dom/</guid>
      <description>Definition  DOM: Document Object Model An object-based representation of the source HTML document An interface to web pages; an API to the page  Functions  Allows browsers to determine what to render in the viewport Allows JavaScript to manipulate the page&amp;rsquo;s content, structure, and styles  DOM vs. HTML DOM is not HTML. It is an interface to valid HTML documents. They differ from one another for a number of reasons:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Primitive and Non-Primitive Data Types</title>
      <link>https://haleyjung.github.io/posts/2022/01/primitive-and-non-primitive-data-types/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 12:53:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haleyjung.github.io/posts/2022/01/primitive-and-non-primitive-data-types/</guid>
      <description>Definitions Data Type There is a variety of data types, such as number, boolean, string, null, undefined, etc.
Primitive Data Type  Numbers Strings Booleans undefined null  Primitives are stored by value.
Every time a new variable is declared using a primitive data type, a new address in memory is created for that value.
let a = 1; let b = a;  a has value of 1, which is a Number, a Primitive data type.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CDN: Content Delivery Networks</title>
      <link>https://haleyjung.github.io/posts/2022/01/cdn-content-delivery-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 11:27:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haleyjung.github.io/posts/2022/01/cdn-content-delivery-networks/</guid>
      <description>Definition  CDN is a group of geographically distributed servers that speed up the delivery of web content by caching contents in proxy servers near to the user&amp;rsquo;s physical location. Leads to a faster and high performance of activities such as watching a movie, downloading a software, checking a bank balance, posting on social media, and making a transaction.  Purpose  Users experience a consistent, faster, and high performance web application.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
