<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Debugging on Today I Learned</title>
    <link>https://haleyjung.github.io/tags/debugging/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Debugging on Today I Learned</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 09:33:30 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://haleyjung.github.io/tags/debugging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chrome DevTools: Debugging JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://haleyjung.github.io/posts/2022/01/chrome-devtools-debugging-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 09:33:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haleyjung.github.io/posts/2022/01/chrome-devtools-debugging-javascript/</guid>
      <description>Step 1: Reproduce the bug Finding a series of actions that consistently reproduces a bug is always the first step to debugging.
Step 2: Get familiar with the Sources panel UI After opening the DevTools by pressing Command+Option+J on Mac, click the Sources tab. This is where we debug JavaScript. It has 3 main parts:
(1) Top left: File Navigator pane
This is where we can see and inspect every files that the page requests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Approach to Problem Solving</title>
      <link>https://haleyjung.github.io/posts/2022/01/approach-to-problem-solving/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 10:26:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haleyjung.github.io/posts/2022/01/approach-to-problem-solving/</guid>
      <description>IOCE: Input, Output, Constraints, Edge Cases  Identifying the input(s), output(s), constrains, and edge cases is important as we need to know what the inputs and expected outputs are for a problem, which also reflects my understanding of the prompt.  Strategy(s): How can I get from my input to my output?  A moment to be extra verbal and thinking out loud to brainstorm strategies After brainstorming the first strategy (write quick notes about it to remember), I can also come up with a second strategy, then identify trade-off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging &amp; Common Errors</title>
      <link>https://haleyjung.github.io/posts/2021/12/debugging-common-errors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 14:19:57 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haleyjung.github.io/posts/2021/12/debugging-common-errors/</guid>
      <description>Steps to Debugging 1. Problem Identification  Identify the immediate goal and what needs to be done to achieve it in this moment Investigate how the current state of code differs from the outcome I expect. Understand stack traces (&amp;ldquo;a report of the active stack frames at a certain point in time during the execution of a program&amp;rdquo;) from the error messages:  Failing tests Errors in console Unresponsive page Undesirable behavior   Questions I can ask myself to identify why there is an error:  Are there any syntax errors?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
